{
    "id": "fa8c2b0a7e3442b48bc512805cf16a3f",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I find the key I …………………….. it to you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will give",
                "would give",
                "would have given"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e5c14712383948edbc76fa7101b8716f"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ……………………… hard, you would get the first rank.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would / could / might + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "study",
                "studied",
                "had studied"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a64828c5894048a09a3f925e3c8dc4a5"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she finds out we ………………………. in trouble.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2bd178170e6c4f7fbc6210c0e9b7ef0a"
        },
        {
            "question": "If it is late, we ……………………….. out now.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "cannot go",
                "could not go",
                "could not have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "032cc0f5c7d1423692c0586e08b7c0fb"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………. non-stop, your health will suffer.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "work",
                "worked",
                "had worked"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2ee851f65f4a4863a42579848d04bd60"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had gone to university, I …………………………… a better job.",
            "description": "In the third conditional use a past perfect tense in the if clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "can find",
                "could find",
                "could have found"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "072f4fce1ece4902bf6ae2db3120ff00"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ……………………….. that dog alone, it wouldn’t have bitten you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "leave",
                "had left",
                "left"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "79dcb45f14e94830a927410600b8a6d1"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had listened to me, you …………………………….. in trouble.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will not be",
                "would not be",
                "would not have been"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3165ddef6019439e95e489cb6f0a8dcb"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ………………………. guests tomorrow, I will not be able to come with you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "will have"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f2f4a2afe1104701874db86a5e030f67"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………. a billionaire, how would you spend your money?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "were",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b40797851f6443fe8e390e6c91ac0c26"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I were you, I …………………………. this.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will not tolerate",
                "would not tolerate",
                "would not have tolerated"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1cd89c03dbea4b4093669bdc92751573"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had asked me, I …………………………. you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will tell",
                "would tell",
                "would have told"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "276ceb67c1a349a8a791e2cc20f8c854"
        }
    ]
}